時は戦国、乱世の時代。
からくり人の住むジパング国では群雄割拠して合戦に明け暮れ、
からくり武芸者たちも勝利と栄光を目指してしのぎを削っていた。
そしていま、からくり武芸者ナンバー１を目指す、とてつもないヒーローが誕生した！
ムサシ、見参でござるだス！
からくり剣豪伝ムサシロード
男はいつでも　世界の真ん中で
いちばん　強くなる日を
AH! AH! 夢見て
心の刃　大空にふりかざし
冒険の旅の　幕を開ける
ジパング国を　さすらう剣豪
その名　からくりびと　ムサシ
GO! FIGHT!
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　昨日よりも　今日　強い
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
明日は　輝くぞ
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　思い切りと　静けさと
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
みけんが　きらめいた　ムサシ！！
지팡구국 제일의 무예가를 꿈꾸는 무사시는 무수한 무예가와 검을 주고받고 있었지만
Dreaming for the number one martial artist of Jipangu State, Musashi was fighting against numberless Martial Artists,
상대를 잘못 만났다. 지금은 전국에서 많은 회원을 가진 악명 높은 요시오카 도장의 보스,
but he met a wrong opponent, the infamous Denshichirō, the boss of Yoshika Dōjō
덴시치로를 적으로 맞이하고야 말았다.
boasting countless members across the land.
명검 코테츠, 폭풍을 부르오
Kotetsu the Excellent Sword
Calls for a Storm
그런 목검으로 승부를 보다니 가소롭기 짝이 없구나! 무예가의 승부라는 것은 이런 진검을 써서 하는 것이다!
That's very absurd, to have a match with that wooden sword!
A match between martial artists shall only be done with real swords like this!
당했소! 나, 죽겠소! 누가 살려주시오!
I lost! I'm going to die-dasu! Someone help me-dasu!
얘야. 뭘 자면서 그러니.
Kid, you're half asleep.
이건 감이었소...
It was a persimmon-dasu!
아까 감나무 아래 지나가는 중에 떨어졌나 보구나.
We were going under a persimmon tree moments ago.
무슨 꿈을 꾸고 있었는지는 모르겠지만 크게 흥분하고 있었구나.
I don't know what were you dreaming about, but you were pretty agitated.
젠장, 나도 칼을 원하오.
Damn, I want a sword too-dasu.
칼을 손에 넣어 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 되겠소!
I will get a sword and become the number one martial artist of Jipangu-dasu!
어이! 이제 곧 사카이 마을이다.
We're soon at Sakai village.
사카이에 오신 것을 환영합니다
Welcome to Sakai
이곳은 상인의 마을로 번영한 사카이 항구.
This place is Sakai harbor, a village of merchants.
덴시치로는 무사시를 쫒으려 이곳 요시오카 도장 사카이 지점에 왔다.
Denshichiro came to Yoshioka Dōjō Sakai branch to get Musashi.
(주) 요시오카 도장
Yoshioka Dōjō Inc.
사카이 지점
Sakai Branch
(주) 요시오카 도장
사카이 지점
환영
Yoshioka Dōjō Inc.
Sakai Branch
Welcome
이 자가 우리 요시오카 도장에 행패를 부린 무사시의 얼굴이다.
This is the face of Musashi who wreaked havoc on our Yoshioka Dōjō.
매우 교활한 얼굴이군!
What a sly face!
무도는 형태이다
Martial Arts is about Form
녀석은 틀림없이 이 사카이 마을에 있을 터이다. 알겠나?
He should be in this Sakai village. Understood?
샅샅이 뒤져서라도 녀석을 찾아내어 발견하면 바로 이 나에게 알려라!
Search for him thoroughly and report to me as soon as you find out where he is!
애송이라 생각될 테지만 방심하면 큰일난다!
He is not just a weak brat, so be careful!
예!
Got it!
스승님!
Master!
뭔가?
What is it?
예의 칼 장인이 오셨습니다.
The sword craftsman you asked for is here.
좋다. 지금 가겠다.
Good. I'll go right now.
이 인물, 켄모치 코테츠야말로, 지팡구국의 기나긴 전국 시대의 역사적으로 유명한 칼 장인이다.
This person, Kenmochi Kotetsu, is a historically famous sword craftsman of the long Sengoku period of Jipangu State.
코테츠 작
Made by Kotetsu
그가 만든 칼은 코테츠라 불리며, 검의 길을 끝까지 걸은 자만이 손에 넣을 수 있다고 불려진다.
A sword crafted by him is called Kotetsu, and it is told that only masters of swords can have one.
나는 요시오카 도장의 대리 사범, 요시오카 덴시치로라고 하오.
I am Denshichirō Yoshioka, a substitute instructor at Yoshioka Dōjō.
켄모치 코테츠이오.
Kenmochi Kotetsu.
본론부터 말하자면, 내게 명도 코테츠를 만들어 주셨으면 한다.
Long story short, I'd like to ask you to make your excellent sword Kotetsu.
거절하오.
I reject.
뭐라?! 이 요시오카 도장의 대리 사범의 요청을 거절한다고?
What?! You dare to reject the request from the substitute instructor at Yoshioka Dōjō?
너, 설마 지팡구국에 이름을 떨치는 요시오카 덴시치로 님을 모르는 것인가?
Don't you know Yoshioka Denshichirō, a name famous all over Jipangu State?
이름은 안다.
I do know.
그럼 어째서 거절하나? 칼을 만드는 게 그렇게 체면 구기는 일은 아니지 않소이까.
Then why do you reject? Crafting a sword isn't something dishonorable.
안됐지만 이미 칼 만드는 것은 그만두었소.
I regret to say that I already gave up crafting swords.
관두었다?
Gave up?
어떤가. 돈이라면 얼마라도 주겠다.
How's this? We'll pay as much as you want.
난 돈 따위를 원하는 것이 아니다.
I do not want money.
그렇다면 무엇을 바라는가?
Then what do you want?
아무것도.
Nothing special.
욕심 없는 녀석이군. 그러나 잘 기억해 두어라.
I see that you are without greed. But know this.
네게 어떤 사정이 있던간, 이 내게 칼을 하나 만들어 바쳐야 할 것이다.
Whatever reason you have, you will make and give me a sword.
실례하오.
Excuse me.
잠깐! 아직 이야기가 끝나지 않았다!
Wait! He is not done yet!
기한은 10일간!
I will allow you ten days!
이 내가 직접 가지러 가겠다. 알겠나?
I will go receive it myself. Understood?
괜찮습니까?
Are you alright with this?
이 지팡구가 넓을 망정 일찍이 내 부탁을 거절한 자는 없었다.
No matter how wide Jipangu is, nobody dared to deny my request.
더욱, 거절한 것으로 생명을 잃은 자는 수를 셀 수가 없군.
Moreover, I can't count how many people lost their lives by denying my request.
나... 배고파 죽겠소...
I am starved to death-dasu...
이, 이건 단고의 향이오!
This smell must be dango-dasu!
단고 5문
차 1문
Dango 5 mon
Tea 1 mon
아... 뱃가죽이 등에 붙고야 말겠소.
My belly's going to meet my back-dasu...
알바모집
시간당 3문
교통비 지급
식사 제공
아무나 가능
사카이 긴자 634-5
음악찻집
Part Time Job Notice
3 mons an hour
Traffic expenses provided
Meal provided
Immediate interview
Sakai Ginja 634-5
Musical Tea House
식사
Meal provided
우와! 하늘의 도움이오!
Wow! It's a help from the heavens-dasu!
모두! 타셨습니까?
Are you ready?!
네!
Yes!
좋아, 바로 일해 볼까? 일은 간단해.
Alright, let's get you working right away. Your job is simple.
주문이 들어오면 가져다 주기만 하면 돼.
Bring these whenever there is an order.
저, 식사는 몇시이오?
When is the mealtime-dasu?
일하고 나서 식사다.
After you work.
네.
Okay.
3번 테이블 단고 한 접시!
One dango plate on the 3th table!
네! 단고 한 접시!
Got it! One dango plate!
어이, 어이, 빨리 가져다 줘!
Hey, hey! Hurry up and bring it!
네, 네, 네!
Yes, sir!
아, 이곳이오!
Here it is-dasu!
기다리셨소!
Here is your order-dasu!
어라? 오츠루 씨!
Huh? Otsuru!
뭐에요?
What is it?
역시 오츠루 씨인 것이오! 나이오!
You're Otsuru-dasu! It's me-dasu!
전 당신이 누군지 몰라요.
I don't know who you are.
에이, 장난은 관두고 나이오, 나! 미야모토 마을의 무사시오!
Don't joke on me-dasu! I am Musashi, from Miyamoto village-dasu!
무사시라니 몰라요!
I don't know anyone named Musashi!
무사시?
Musashi?
오츠루 씨, 나에요, 나!
Otsuru, it's me!
뭔 소리에요! 내 이름은 오타마에요!
What are you talking about?! My name is Otama!
오츠루 씨도 참 화나면 귀엽소...
Otsuru, you're cute when you're angry-dasu...
뭔 짓이야! 아무나! 이 사람 치한이에요!
What are you doing?! Help me! A pervert!
아, 아니오! 아니오!
No, that's not it! There's a misunderstanding-dasu!
이러면 곤란해. 그러지 않아도 최근 학부모회가 시끄럽게 구는데.
That was pretty bad. We don't need to trigger PTA any further...
죄송하오...
I'm sorry-dasu...
네게 식당 앞 일은 어울리지 않는 것 같으니 저기서 단고 막대기라도 깎아라.
It seems that you're not suited for working at the front of house. Maybe you're better off with carving dango sticks.
저, 식사는...
Uh, the meal...
-아직아직!
-네...
-Not yet!
-Okay...
이 찻집 안에서 무사시가 일하고 있습니다.
Musashi is working in this tea house.
무사시 놈, 오늘로써 끝장을 내 주겠다!
Musashi, you're going down as of today!
알겠나? 절대 무사시를 놓치면 안 된다!
Understand? Do not let Musashi run away!
예!
Roger!
오? 네게도 하나 잘 하는 것이 있구나.
Oh , at least you have a specialty.
무사시는 어디 있나!
Where is Musashi?!
어? 저 목소리는...
That voice...
뭐냐, 뭔 짓이냐?
What are you doing?!
비켜라! 무사시가 있다!
Move away! Musashi is here!
무사시! 각오해라!
Musashi! Prepare yourself!
무사시 저깄다!
There's Musashi!
멈춰라!
Stop!
무사시가 저 지붕에서 달아난다!
Musashi is running away on that roof!
젠장, 끈덕지오!
They're damn persistent-dasu!
어라?
Huh?
무사시! 각오해라.
Musashi! Prepare yourself.
젠장! 자, 하려면 하시오! 겨우 하나 대 여럿이라니 비겁하오!
Dammit! Do as you want-dasu! One vs many is cowardly-dasu!
비겁이라고 말하면 안 된다. 너 따위는 나 혼자서도 충분하다!
Do not call this cowardly. I am more than enough to finish you!
오츠루 씨! 먼저 다음 세계로 가겠소!
Otsuru! I'm going to the next world earlier than you-dasu!
무사시 놈! 쫒아라! 쫒아!
Damn that Musashi! Follow him! Find him!
무슨 일이오?
What's going on-dasu?
자! 이 틈이다! 따라와!
Now! Run away! Come!
살았소...
What a relief-dasu...
감사하...
I must say thank...
코지로!
Kojirō!
예의 모르는 놈. 생명의 은인 이름을 막 부르는 놈이 있는가!
You insolent brat. How rude of you to call the name of your lifesaver without respect!
미안하오!
Sorry-dasu!
고맙소.
Thank you-dasu.
그, 근데 왜 날 구했소?
Bu- but why did you saved me-dasu?
너같은 꼬맹이 하나를 다 자란 성인 여럿이서 쫒아다니는 요시오카의 짓은 용서할 수 없기 때문이다!
I cannot forgive how the numerous grown-ups at Yoshioka are trying to chase a young kid like you!
난 얘가 아니오!
I am not a kid!
그럼 넌 뭐냐?
Then what are you?
나, 이렇게 보여도 무예가라오!
I am a martial artist despite how I look-dasu!
흥, 웃기지 마라! 자기 칼도 없는 얘가! 부끄러운 줄 모르는 놈!
Hmph, don't make me laugh! You don't even have your own sword! You should be ashamed!
그, 그건 너무했소!
Th- that's too much!
검은 무사의 생명! 검을 가지지 않는 놈을 무사로는 인정할 수 없다!
A sword is the life of a martial artist! I will not accept whoever without a sword as a martial artist!
이 칼은 명도 세키노마고로쿠(関の孫六). 통칭 모노호시자오(物干し竿)다.
This excellent sword is Seki no Magoroku, also known as Monohoshizao.
잘 봐 두어라!
Feast your eyes!
흥. 바보 놈.
Hmph. Idiot.
뭐시라?!
What did you say-dasu?!
멋진 척 하지 마시오!
You're a showoff-dasu!
살았소...
That was close-dasu...
코지로 놈!
Damn that Kojirō!
코지로에게 놀림받은 무사시. 칼을 손에 넣을 수 있을 것인가? 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Musashi was insulted by Kojirō. Will he ever get a sword? Wait for the stormy latter half!
잡았소!
Caught one-dasu!
배고프오...
Hungry-dasu...
자, 무사시 씨. 제가 만든 주먹밥이에요. 많이 드세요!
Here, Musashi. I made these rice balls for you. Eat as much as you want!
고맙소, 오츠루 씨. 잘 먹겠소!
Thank you for all of these-dasu, Otsuru.
오츠루 씨, 이거 딱딱하오.
Otsuru, these are tough-dasu...
딱딱하오...
Tough...
오츠루 씨...
Otsuru...
먹을 수가 없소.
I can't eat-dasu...
형! 형!
Hey there! Brother!
형 왜 돌을 갉아?
Brother, why are you gnawing on stones?
배, 배가 고파서 못 움직이겠소.
I... I am too hungry to move-dasu.
자, 형! 이거 먹어!
Here, brother! You can have this!
아, 잘 먹었소! 배가 부르오.
That was good! I am full-dasu.
얘야, 고맙소. 형 제정신을 되찾았소!
Thanks to you, kid, that really saved me-dasu!
그래도... 혹시 집으로 가져갈 물고기 아니었소?
But... weren't you going to take that fishes to your home-dasu?
괜찮아! 이걸로 또 잡으면 되니까!
It's all right! I can catch them again with this!
좋아! 그럼 형이 잡아주오!
All right! If that's the case, brother will catch for you-dasu!
해냈소!
I did it!
형 대단해!
You're awesome!
고마워!
Thank you!
아무것도 아니오.
That was nothing-dasu.
그래도 그 작살은 좋은 잘 듣는 칼인데... 누가 만들었소?
But still, that harpoon pierces pretty nicely... Who made it?
이건 아빠가 만들었어!
My dad made this!
아빠?
Dad?
지팡구 제일의 칼 장인, 켄모치 코테츠라고 해!
The number one sword craftsman of Jipangu, Kenmochi Kotetsu!
난 그 자식 코타로!
I am his son, Kotarō!
럭키하오!
Lucky-dasu!
안된다, 안 돼!
Nope, no way.
그런 말 하지 마시고 어떻게든 부탁드리오!
Don't say that, and please help-dasu!
나, 어떻게든 명인의 칼을 원하오!
I really want a sword from a master craftsman-dasu!
난 칼 장인은 관뒀다!
I gave up being one!
딱 하나만, 어떻게든, 절 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 되게 해 주시오!
Please, just one for me! Help me become the number one martial artist of Jipangu!
그러나 지팡구 제일이 되는 건 네 노력이다. 내가 그렇게 해주는 게 아니라!
But it's your effort alone that will make you become the number one in Jipangu. I can't make you become one!
알고 있소! 저, 지금부터 목숨을 걸고 노력하겠소.
I already know-dasu! From now on, I'll risk my life for that-dasu.
그래도... 그래도...
But... still...
나... 어떻게든 명인의 칼을 원하오...
I... really want a sword from a master craftsman-dasu...
부탁드리오! 명인의 칼을 갖고 싶소!
Please-dasu! I want a sword from an expert-dasu!
원하오!
I want one-dasu!
곤란한 놈이군.
What should I do with him?
칼 갖고 싶소!
I want a sword-dasu!
칼...
Sword...
무사시는 한번 정하면 끈덕졌다.
Once decided, Musashi was persistent.
부탁드리오! 어떻게든 칼을 원하오!
Please-dasu! I want a sword no matter whatever it takes-dasu!
부탁드리오! 명인의 칼이 갖고 싶소!
Please-dasu! I want a sword of an expert-dasu!
-어떻게든 부탁드리오! 돈도 드리겠소!
-아빠...
-Please help me-dasu! I'll pay you-dasu!
-Dad...
부탁드리오! 나, 지팡구 제일의 무예가로...
Please-dasu! I need to be the number one martial artist of Jipangu...
보쿠덴 스승님... 분하오...
Master Bokuden... I am so mortified-dasu...
보쿠덴?
Bokuden?
나, 이제 지팡구 제일이 되지 못하오...
I won't be able to become the number one anymore...
어이! 무사시! 일어나라!
Hey! Musashi! Wake up!
아, 아! 좋은 아침이오.
Ah! Good morning-dasu.
몇 가지 묻겠다만, 네 검의 스승은 누구냐?
I must ask you; who is the master you learned swordsmanship from?
제 스승은 츠카하라 보쿠덴이오.
My master is Tsukahara Bokuden-dasu.
거짓말하지 마라! 보쿠덴 님은 제자를 받지 않을 터이다!
Do not lie! Bokuden does not take students!
그, 근데 나 틀림없이 제자이오.
Bu- but I really am his student-dasu.
그렇다면 보쿠덴 님의 검의 궁극의 목적을 말해 보아라!
Then tell me, the ultimate purpose of a sword, according to Master Bokuden!
어... 뭐였더라?
Uh... what was it?
-왜 그러나?
-저...
-What's the problem?
-Um...
역시 가짜구나!
You were lying at all!
난 거짓말은 하지 않소!
I do not lie-dasu!
그럼 대 보아라!
Then tell me right now!
안 되겠어, 이 녀석.
This is going nowhere.
아! 잠깐! 기억났소!
Wait! Just a moment! I remembered!
검의 궁극은 싸우지 않고 이기는 것. 무도의 무(武) 자는 원래 창(戈)을 막는다(止)는 의미, 즉, 무기를 멈추는 것.
The true meaning of a sword is to win without fighting.
Solidness(武) of martial arts(武道) originally means to stop(止) a spear(戈); in other words, to stop a weapon.
노자(老子)는 적을 잘 이기는 자는 싸우지 않는다고 했소.
To borrow the words of Laozi, the one who easily defeats an enemy does not engage.
잘 했다!
Good job!
예! 감사하오.
Yes! Thank you-dasu.
애초에 내가 칼 장인를 관둔 것에는 이유가 있다.
I have a reason why I stopped being a sword craftsman.
먼저 어떠한 검에도 혼이 깃들어 있음을 알고,
First, you must know that a sword has a spirit.
검에는 그것을 만든 자와 쓰는 자의 생각이 담겨 있다.
A sword inherits the mind of the crafter and the yielder.
그 마음이 부정한 자라면 검은 사견이 되어,
To one with a wicked mind, the sword would also become so,
단지 생명을 빼앗는 도구에 불과하다. 알겠나?
ending up as nothing more than a tool to take lives away. Do you understand?
잘은 모르겠지만 나는 사람을 죽이기 위해 칼을 쓰지 않소.
I don't really understand-dasu, but I don't use swords to kill people-dasu.
잘 말했다, 무사시. 네 눈이 참 맑구나.
Well said, Musashi. Your eyes are clear.
잘 자고 난 후니까...
Because I had a good sleep.
무사시. 잘 들어라. 나는 널 위해 다시 한번만 칼을 만들겠다.
Musashi, listen well. I will make swords for you for the last time.
저, 정말이오?
Re- really?!
그러나, 너도 함께 검을 만드는 자의 마음을 배우는 것이 좋다.
But you will have to learn the mind of sword craftsman.
네!
Right!
일본도의 재료는 땅 안에 오랫동안 잠자고 있던 순도가 높은 사철이다.
The material of Japanese swords is iron sand of high purity that slept for a long time under the grond.
그 사철을 몇천 회, 몇만 회 마음을 담아 단련시켜 만드는 것이다.
The iron sand must be forged thousands and millions of times wholeheartedly in order to make one.
아직 안 된 걸까나...
I wonder if they're still not done yet...
-해냈다!
-해냈구나!
-We did it!
-해냈소! 만세이오!
-참 잘 했다!
-We did it-dasu! Hooray-dasu!
-Good job!
무사시, 이것이 내가 이 세상에서 만든 마지막 검일 테다. 마음을 담아 써라.
Musashi, these will be the last swords that I make in this world. Use them to the fullest.
정말 감사하오.
Thank you so much-dasu.
코테츠 님! 어라? 나도 갑자기 피곤해졌...
Master Kotetsu! Huh? I suddenly got sleepy...
여보! 큰일입니다!
Dear! Big problem!
무, 무슨 일인가?
Wha- what's going on?
요시오카 도장의 사람들이 와서...
People from Yoshioka Dōjō came and...
뭐라? 내가 부탁한 칼을 만들지 않겠다고?
What? He didn't made the sword I asked?
어떤 분의 의뢰라도 들을 수 없습니다!
We will not accept any request from anyone!
그렇다면 어떻게든 만들게 하겠다!
Then I'll make him make one!
-어이!
-예!
-You know what to do!
-Yes!
뭘 하시는 것입니까!
What are you doing?!
살려줘! 무서워!
Help! I'm scared!
네 아이는 코테츠의 검과 교환하겠다. 그렇게 전해라!
I will exchange your child for a sword made by Kotetsu. Tell him so!
살려줘!
Help me!
코타로!
Kotarō!
이 무슨 비열한 패거리오. 코타로는 이 목숨과 교환해서라도 구해내겠소!
What a cowardly gang. I will save Kotarō even if I have to exchange my life for him-dasu!
코타로! 기다리시오!
Kotarō! I'm going to save you-dasu!
(주) 요시오카 도장
사카이 지점
Yoshioka Dōjō Inc.
Sakai Branch
무사시가 왔다!
Musashi has appeared!
-무사시가!
-네이놈!
-Musashi!
-How dare you!
무사시! 등장이오!
Musashi is here-dasu!
걱정할 필요는 없소! 칼등이오!
No need to worry-dasu! It was the back side-dasu!
무사시, 각오해라!
Prepare yourself, Musashi!
뭐냐, 저 자세는!
What is that posture?
무사시! 이게 눈에 들어오지 않는가!
Musashi! Don't you see this?!
코, 코타로!
Ko- Kotarō!
쓸데없는 저항은 관둬라! 그렇지 않으면 이 얘의 목숨은 없다!
Give up with your futile resistance! Or this kid dies!
무사시! 칼을 내려둬라!
Musashi! Put down your sword!
아, 아빠!
D- dad!
코타로!
Kotarō!
용서할 수 없소, 덴시치로!
Unforgivable, Densichirō!
사, 살려줘. 돈이라면 얼마라도 줄 테니!
Spare me. I'll give you money as much as you want!
용서할 수 없소! 넌 지옥으로 보내주겠소!
Unforgivable-dasu! I will send you to hell-dasu!
무사시! 관두지 못할까!
Musashi! Stop that right now!
멈추지 마시오!
Don't stop me-dasu!
벌써 잊었냐, 무사시! 검은 위해를 가하기 위해 쓰이는 것이 아니라고!
Did you forget already, Musashi?! A sword does not exist to injure a person!
보쿠덴 님도 그렇게 말했을 테다!
Master Bokuden would said so too!
이 놈을 죽이면 검이 더럽혀질 뿐이다!
If you kill this guy, you just end up disgracing your sword!
아, 알겠소.
Alright-dasu.
이렇게 무사시는 명도 코테츠를 손에 넣었다.
And this is how Musashi has managed to get the excellent swords, Kotetsu.
그리고 또 그 날, 그 유명한 이도류가 탄생한 것이었지만,
And also, on that day, that famous dual blade has born,
무사시는 아직 깨닫지 못하였다.
but Musashi is yet to realize.
カラのポケットに　ツキが
飛び込むことも　あるさ
おっきな声で　笑えば
あしたには　朝が来る
無くすものなんか　何もないさ
やっちゃえ！イケイケ！
手ぶらは　強いぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
人生　てなもんさ　チャンスが　ほら
しっぽを振って　追ってくるぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
未来も　てなもんさ　あしたが　ほら
両手ひろげて　笑ってるぜ
스승, 좋은 울림을 가진 단어이오.
Master. A word with good echo-dasu.
결국엔 나도 제자를 가지게 되었소!
Finally, I got a student-dasu!
제자라는 것은 편리하오! 돈 걱정 없이 단고를 먹게 해 주고, 길을 안내해 주고.
A student is convinient! He lets me eat dangos without worry, and guides my path.
근데 이 제자라는 자, 나보다 강하오...
But this student is powerful than me, heh...
다음 이야기! 나는 스승이오. 훌륭하오!
Next story! I am a Master! Excellent!
질풍노도의 활약을 보시오!
Be sure to check out the next stormy story-dasu!
다음 이야기
나는 스승이오
훌륭하오!
기대하세요!
Next Episode
I am a Master
Excellent!
Look forwards for it!